rotogrinders.com 2019-11-15

# RotoGrinders: The Daily Fantasy Sports Authority

## RotoGrinders Privacy Policy

## Introduction

A RotoGrinder user ( _‘you’_ ) may participate in available forum in order to share information and opinions on sport matches, search for and post tips, check the match statistics, get reviews of bookmakers, information about free bets, and other topics ( _‘services’_ ). More about our services is available in our Terms and Conditions. When you use our services your information might be shared with us or third parties. 

This Privacy Policy is important to you to understand how your personal data is collected, used, consulted or otherwise processed when you use _<https://rotogrinders.com/>_ ( _‘Rotogrinders’_ ). Personal data is any information about you that might be used to identify you, or make possible to identify you. This Privacy Policy applies to your personal data processing on Rotogrinders, and not to data processing that may occur on other services or web pages regardless whether they are provided by the owner of Rotogrinders of someone else. The owner of Rotogrinders ( _‘we’, ‘us’, ‘our’_ ) is:

**BC Tennessee**

**209 10th Ave S**

**Nashville, TN 37203**

This Privacy Policy is effective from 10th September 2019. This Privacy Policy may be modified from time-to-time.

Essential modifications are those that affect your rights, obligations and state with regard to protection and processing of your personal data. The essential modifications might include (but not limited to) launch of new services, deployment of new technologies and processing your data for new purposes. Therefore, if we make essential modifications to the Privacy Policy, we will send you notice through our Services, or by other means, and give you the opportunity to review the changes before they become effective. 

In addition, from time to time we make minor modifications of the Privacy Policy. Minor modifications do not impact your rights, obligations and state with regard to protection of personal data. These types of modifications might include (but are not limited to) organizational and grammatical changes to this Privacy Policy in order to make our policy easier to read. 

## Data Controller and Data Subjects 

By using Rotogrinders services you may disclose various pieces of information, including those that would be considered personal data. When your personal data is processed then you are considered a data subject and you are entitled to exercise your rights that are explained in this Privacy Policy. Taking into account that we determine the purposes and means of processing personal data on Rotogrinders we are legally considered as data controller over your personal data on this website. Being data controller provides us the opportunity to process your personal data, but also obliges us to protect them. 

## Data we process 

We are processing (or might process) various categories of your data. Below you may find information on which data we process, as well as their categorizations. 

## Identification data 

**Personal Identifiable Information (PII)** \- When you create your account on Rotogrinders, we process your name, email and username you choose. 

**Electronic identification data** \- When you logging in to the Rotogrinders we process the IP address of the device you use, the type and version of browser and operating system you use as well as the time of signing in. 

## Private habits and interests

**Preferences** \- We process the information how and which services you use. Also, we process information provided to us when you contact us.

## Why we process your data and how

We collect and process data about you when you sign up and use our service. We process your personal data in order to provide our services to you, to improve your experience about our services, to further develop our service, and to secure and maintain regular functioning of RotoGrinders. More about purposes for processing your data you may find below. 

## Identification data

**Personal Identifiable Information (PII) -** Your PII that we process when you create the account serve to distinguish you from other Rotogrinders users. Your PII is required in order to register and we use it to communicate with you regarding any changes to your account or our services, as well as for commercial communication if you agree to receive it. 

**Electronic identification data -** We process the IP address of the device you use in order to enable communication between your device and our server; to determine your approximate geolocation which may be further used for service customization (for instance to provide appropriate content for your language of choice and gambling-related content that is legal in your country) as well as for analytical purposes. More about how we process your data for analytical purposes you may find in our Cookie Policy.

The processing of details about the browser and operating system you use is necessary to ensure the regular provision of our services to you. Also, sometimes we will need this data to solve some technical problems if they emerge. 

## Private habits and interests

**Preferences** \- We process information about your preferences in order to send you notifications when something new is posted. Also, we need to know as well whether you opted in for newsletter, so that we can send you news and updates on a regular basis. 

## Our use of cookies

Any browser visiting our Website will receive cookies from us. We use cookies because we wish to provide the best possible on-site experience to everyone who visits our website.

By the use of cookies we process standard internet log information and details of Website visitors behaviour patterns. The use of cookies enable us to improve site navigation, analyse on-site behaviour of everyone who visits the website, promote our products and provide content from third parties. To find out more about our use of cookies, read our Cookie Policy. 

## How we protect your data 

We do not collect personal data in excessive manner. We only process data that we really need and only for agreed purposes. We are tending to keep your data up to date and to store them securely. We do not process your data for a period longer than it is necessary for the purposes for which data is processed. 

We use technical and organisational measures in accordance with good industry practice to safeguard your information. Thus, we take appropriate technical and organizational measures to ensure protection of your personal data against accidental or unlawful loss, alteration, steal, unauthorized disclosure or access, unauthorized use and against all other unlawful forms of processing.

We apply different levels of access control to your data. Restriction of access control is based on business needs and security requirements. We ensure you that only appropriately authorized persons have access to your data, whose knowledge and skills about data is necessary to fulfill their obligations arising out of or in connection with the performance of their job. 

## Your rights 

## Right to access 

You have the right to obtain from us confirmation as to whether or not personal data concerning you is processed, and, where that is the case, to request access to the personal data. If you would like to get the confirmation as well as the access to your personal data please send contact us via _[dataprotection@ bettercollective.com](mailto:dataprotection@bettercollective.com)_ .

## Right to rectification 

You have the right to ask us to delete inaccurate personal data concerning you. Taking into account the purposes of the data processing, you have the right to have incomplete personal data completed. 

## Right to erasure (right to be forgotten) 

In limited circumstances, you will have the right to request that we erase the information we hold about you: 

  * where the data is no longer needed for the purposes it was collected, 
  * where you have withdrawn consent and there is no other lawful basis on which we can continue to process it, 
  * where you objected to processing and there are no overriding legitimate grounds to continue, 
  * where the data has been unlawfully processed or 
  * where the data has to be erased for compliance with a legal obligation. 

## Right to restrict processing 

You have the right to seek the restriction of processing of your personal data in the following circumstances:

  * If the accuracy of the data is contested – processing may be restricted for the period necessary to allow us to verify its accuracy,
  * the processing is unlawful and you request restriction instead of erasure,
  * we no longer need the data for the purposes it was collected, but you need it in connection with a legal claim,
  * if you objected to the processing of personal data that are processed on the grounds of our legitimate interests, while awaiting verification whether our legitimate interests ground for processing your data overrides interest of your fundamental rights and freedoms.

## Right to object to the processing of your data and rights related to automated decision making 

You have the right to object our processing of your data on grounds relating to your particular situation, at any time to the processing of your personal data, including profiling. Upon your objection, we will stop processing your data unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for continuing the processing which override interests of your fundamental freedoms and rights, or if further processing is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims. 

At any time you have the right to object processing your data, including profiling, for direct marketing purposes. We might use tools for automated decision making including profiling, for marketing purposes, and you may opt-out from further data processing for this purpose. More details about opt-out are given in the Cookie Policy. Upon your opt-out your personal data will not be longer processed for direct marketing purposes. In regard with automated decision making about you, you may have right to request human intervention.

## Right to data portability 

Under certain circumstances you have right to receive your personal data, which you have provided to us, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format (i.e. in digital form) and you have the right to request the transmission of those data to another entity without hindrance from us, if such transmission is technically feasible. 

## Right to withdraw consent 

If the ground for processing your personal data is your consent, you can withdraw your consent at any time without giving any reason to us, and free of charge. 

The withdrawal of consent does not affect the lawfulness of processing based on consent before its withdrawal. Please be aware that after withdrawal of the consent we will not be able to process your data and consequently we will not be able to offer our services to you. 

## Right to lodge a complaint 

If you feel that your personal data rights have been breached, you can contact us on _[dataprotection@ bettercollective.com](mailto:dataprotection@bettercollective.co)_. You also have the right to lodge a complaint with your local data protection authority. 

## How to exercise your rights

If you have any questions or doubts regarding the processing of your personal data, or you wish to exercise your rights explained above, please feel free to send an email to _[dataprotection@ bettercollective.com](mailto:dataprotection@bettercollective.com)_. 

## How long we keep your data 

We keep your data until you delete your account on RotoGrinders. When you delete your account we erase your personal data. 

## Who else may access your data

We may share your data with third parties. The third parties are categorized as follows:

  * Entities who help us to regularly provide, and further develop our services (e.g. analytics, maintenance, marketing, development). They are allowed to process your information as reasonably necessary in order to perform delegated tasks. Please be aware that only we determine the purpose and means of the processing of your data as well as we decide which of your data is going to be processed to perform delegated tasks.
  * With public authorities and law enforcement agencies where it is necessary to do so and where we are legally required or permitted to do so. 
  * Third parties who are granted access to our API, which may show your tips, username, avatar, rating, success of your tip and country 

## Transfer of your data to third countries 

We may transfer your personal data in third countries in order to provide our services on regularly base and/or to further develop our services. We take all measures in relation to the recipients of your personal data, to ensure an adequate level of protection and appropriate safeguards as defined by the applicable data protection law.
